Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 84.
And this exercise, we are going to create the complete binary tree in Java.
So I would create a new Java class called Complete Binary three.
And by the way, you can download all of these source codes from the resource folder on their knees,
every exercise and every lesson that contains source codes.
So class.
Note this is the structure of every node that we are going to create, and the node in the tree contains
the data that you are going to store the data inside it in form of input, and I create the reference
to the left and the reference to the right.
So we need a pointer node left and right, and we create the constructor here.
And I then took into the parameter item and we start initializing any new node by creating the new item
and storing the data inside the new item left equal to the right and pointing left and right equal to
no.
OK.
So any newly created node will look into the meter data and we store inside the state that the item
and we initialize the left and the right to not.
OK, now let's create a new node instance from this class called eroad.
This is the class, and they have created a new object from this class not called rude.
I will start making the methods here.
Here are the methods.
And start building these methods.
First of all, that count count the number of nodes and count num num nodes
node through it, and we check if it is the root equal equal to none, then return zero.
Otherwise, it will return one plus count no number of nodes to the left group to the left.
We count the sub three nodes, the left plus account numbers.
We are using recursion.
You see, guys, this is the recursion symbol.
We are calling the method again and again until we reach that nine.
So this is how we used the recursion to count the now then nodes and if we pass through it to the right.
So guys pay attention.
One is the fort for the root of the three count left item, this is for the left sub three.
And this is for that.
Three.
OK.
And we use detergent in order to count the number of notes.
By the way, we have a stopping condition.
Root equal, equal to null.
So when you reach a note that it's equal to null, then returns zero and start going back, do count
the number of notes to the left.
And when you finish this method, then be able to count the number of notes when you reach until going.
This recursion recursively executing this method.
And when you reach a root equal equal to not the best at the best note.
And the best argument is equal to null, then returns zero and we go back.
Please go back to the recursion section in order to understand the mechanism behind using that character.
OK, now check for it.
Check for complete binary three Boolean Check complete.
We passed the node tree roots, tree and index and end.
No.
I told you in the previous video when we talked about the complete binary tree that every type of the
binary tree is has its key and it's pretty meters.
So we have you used this, the check check complete.
We have used a new method called Check Perfect in the perfect binary tree, and we have passed the root.
We have passed the depth and we have passed the level in the same way.
In the complete, we are using the root index and number of nodes.
So every complete binary, every binary tree has its own specifications and it's it has its own steps
and its own criteria to detect if it is a perfect, if it is incomplete and if it is a binary tree or
not.
So later on, we are going to revise all of these and we will see the the different types and the different
methods that we have made.
OK, so check complete.
We check if that tree is empty, if that he is empty.
If ruled equal, equal to null, then return true.
OK.
This is very is if index greater than or equal to number of nodes that we passed, then return false.
Otherwise we are going to return
check complete using recursion.
So you see guys, how how recursion works in data structure and how it's very important to understand
its basics and to master it.
So we have full full exercise and full section and that it goes into recursion section.
So please go back to the recursion section and practice and master recursion before making these exercises.
So we have checked complete the route to the left to the right now, and we've passed two times the
index.
This is the algorithm behind the index by calculating the index of the complete binary tree.
And now we are surpassing the number of notes.
OK.
If this Boolean expression is true and this Boolean expression true, we have and operator here, then
the returning result would be true if any of them is equal to false and then it will return and false.
So false and false is false, false and true or true and false is equal to false.
OK, this is how we check for their complete binary tree, and it's very important to understand how
it works.
Let's make a driver method.
Main.
Static void main to test our code.
So strange string.
We start by creating a binary tree complete binary three instance three equal to you, complete binary
tree and tree, thought Birdwood.
We start by specifying that it would be equal to a node and it is equal to one.
Now let's start making and think of that
data.
The road to the left equal to a new node two three, though it would build right to equal to a new Node
three.
Maybe there is.
Cannot be referenced from a static context.
Okay, let me make make no static.
OK.
Three.
The truth, though it left is left right.
We have finished left.
And now to that, I equally don't, you know.
And we pass five
three through the left left equal to new nodes.
That's four four.
And the three through both collide the left before two new nodes at six.
So let me make account no, no count equal to.
I will call the three dot count numbers and I've passed the rule for this function and INT index equal
to zero if three dot check, complete with past three Dot Root Index and node count.
If it is true, then display for me systemd.
But the that brain and that three, that three is it complete binary?
Three simple else
point for me is not complete.
But before we start running, I want from you to post a video and tell me the solution of this exercise
in the comment below.
So we have created the route, inserted one inside that we created a new node do and we created to the
right.
Three.
We created to the left of the right and left right.
Five.
Left left, sorry, I have missed this.
We have created to the right.
Off this left, five.
We have created for it.
Left.
Left and the root.
This route, right?
Left.
Is six.
What do you think about this three?
It is complete or not.
Waiting your solution in the comments below.
So let's run and see.
And that this is certainly not we are.
And I mean, the old previously created exercise that three is a complete binary tree, so it's a complete
binary tree.
I want from you to start coding and putting all of these codes in your in your copy, book in your compiler
and save them.
Understand why we are doing this and the idea between every, every tree and every, and how to check
if it is a complete.
How to check if it is perfect.
How to check if it is a binary tree or or other forms of the trees.
A balance tree.
In the next video, we are going to solve this and to understand the balance tree and if this fall binary
tree and so on.
So thank you guys, and I hope you rate us five stars on Udemy.
Support us.